A Guide to the Haigh Jamgochian Papers, circa 1930-2006
Library of Virginia
- Series III. Professional Papers, 1944-2006., Extent: 10 boxes. (Box 4-13)
  - Subseries A. Administrative, 1968-1997., 5 folders.
    Contains various applications, both employment and contest; board registration information; a portfolio of architectural work; and telephone log. The 1968 employment application by the architect is restricted until 29 August 2024. Redacted copy is available.
    - Contest Applications, circa 1997. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Employment Application, 1968. (Box 4, Folder 2)
      RESTRICTED until 29 August 2024. Redacted copy available.
    - National Council of Architectural Registration Boards, 1973-1984. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Portfolio, 1962-1983. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Telephone Log, circa 1962-1965. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B. Clippings/Articles, 1961-2004., 5 boxes.
    Contains extensive print coverage of various projects by architect Jamgochian, as well as articles collected by the architect based on his professional interests. Included are trade magazines, foreign publications, newspaper clippings, professional journals, popular magazines, and the like. In most cases, the entire magazine or journal has been retained. The publications have not been individually foldered but are arranged in chronological order. A marker has been placed to note the location of the article or ad pertaining to Jamgochian, his designs, or similar subject matter.
    Arranged chronologically with loose and undated material at the end.
    - Progressive Architecture- News Report, February 1961. (Box 5)
    - Concrete Products, August 1962. (Box 5)
    - The Commonwealth, January 1963. (Box 5)
    - The New Yorker, March 9, 1963. (Box 5)
    - Playboy, June 1963, September 1964. (Box 5)
      Three copies: one of 1963 and two of 1964.
    - Virginia Record, November 1964. (Box 5)
    - Building Progress, February 1965. (Box 5)
    - Engineering News-Record, February 25, 1965. (Box 5)
    - PC Items, February 1965. (Box 5)
      Three copies.
    - La Technique Des Travaux, May-June 1965. (Box 5)
    - Print, May/June 1965. (Box 5)
    - WFMV Listener's Guide, June 1965. (Box 5)
    - Virginia and The Virginia Record, August 1965. (Box 5)
    - Building With Steel, November 1965. (Box 5)
    - Batir, December 1965. (Box 5)
    - Progressive Architecture, March 1966. (Box 5)
      Two copies.
    - A.I.A. Journal, April 1966. (Box 6)
    - Progressive Architecture, May 1966. (Box 6)
    - Architectural Record, May 1966. (Box 6)
    - Progressive Architecture, November 1966. (Box 6)
    - Architectural Record, November 1966. (Box 6)
    - Virginia Record, November 1966. (Box 6)
    - Glass Digest, January 1967. (Box 6)
    - The Architectural Forum, January-February 1967. (Box 6)
    - Building with Steel, February 1967. (Box 6)
    - The Commonwealth, February 1967. (Box 6)
    - BOCA News, March 1967. (Box 6)
    - La Technique Des Travaux, March-April 1967. (Box 6)
    - Building Progress, May 1967. (Box 6)
    - Frank S. Leake Construction Company Building News Quarterly, Summer 1967. (Box 6)
    - Popular Science, June 1967. (Box 7)
    - Illuminating Engineering, June 1967. (Box 7)
    - Building Progress, July 1967. (Box 7)
    - Industrial Design, July-August 1967. (Box 7)
    - Building, August-September 1967. (Box 7)
      Three copies: two August and one September 1967.
    - Metal Lath News, Fall 1967. (Box 7)
    - Architectural Record, December 1967. (Box 7)
    - Architectural Forum, December 1967. (Box 7)
    - The Lather, December 1967. (Box 7)
    - Metal Lath News, Winter-Spring 1967. (Box 7)
    - Progressive Architecture, January 1968. (Box 7)
    - A.I.A. Journal, April 1968. (Box 7)
    - Batir, April 1968. (Box 8)
    - New Dominion Life Style, May 1975. (Box 8)
    - Progressive Architecture, April 1968. (Box 8)
    - S, B + D [Systems, Building and Design], June 1968. (Box 8)
    - Architectural Record, June 1968. (Box 8)
    - Engineering News-Record, November 14, 1968. (Box 8)
    - Building Construction, June 1969. (Box 8)
    - Virginia Life Style, December 1977. (Box 8)
    - Richmond Guidebook, 1981 Edition. (Box 8)
    - Richmond [Magazine], January, April, May 1995. (Box 8)
      Two copies of each issue.
    - Richmond [Magazine], August 1999. (Box 9)
    - 64, April 2000. (Box 9)
    - Richmond: The City Magazine, December 2001. (Box 9)
      Two copies. Includes two copies of 2002-2003 calendar documenting Richmond architecture. Markel Building and Moon House mentioned.
    - Richmond: The City Magazine, August 2004. (Box 9)
    - Unbound Xerox copies, 1961-2001. (Box 9)
      Contains articles copied from magazines regarding career/work of H. Jamgochian.
  - Subseries C. Correspondence, 1952-1985., 3 folders.
    Contains general correspondence related to the architect's practice. It includes non-project and multi-project correspondence.
    - Correspondence, General, 1952-1966. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, General, 1967. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, General, 1968-1985. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Subseries D. Reference Files, 1965-1990., 10 folders.
    Contains files, manuals, and publications maintained by the architect as reference material. This mostly includes product literature.
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - A, 1965-1985. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - A, 1965-1985. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - B-C, 1966-1985. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - D, circa 1965-1985. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - I, undated. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - L-M, circa 1964-1980. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - N, 1964. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - N, 1980-1989. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - P and Q, circa 1964-1978. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - T-V, circa 1965-1990. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Subseries E. Writings By/About, circa 1962-2001, undated., 19 folders.
    Contains articles, both published and unpublished, by the architect and others concerning his architectural philosophy, designs, controversial stature, and opinions. Some of the materials are copies of term papers given to the architect by students who submitted their work for credit in an art history or related class at the college level. Of note is "The Architecture of Haigh Jamgochian," by Barbara Ross Luck, Virginia Commonwealth University, M. A. Thesis, 1970, and "Architecture Drafting and Design," a textbook, that contains copies of some of Jamgochian's models. Also included in this subseries is a children's book written and illustrated by Jamgochian titled "Little and Big." While this is outside of the architectural profession, it was organized here to maintain one subseries of the architect's writing.
    - "The American Architect...Today," undated. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "Architecture 1967" by Haigh Jamgochian, circa 1967. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Architecture Drafting and Design," 3rd ed., McGraw-Hill Book Co., 1977. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - "The Architecture of Haigh Jamgochian," by Barbara Ross Luck, Virginia Commonwealth University, M. A. Thesis, [Bound], 1970. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - "The Architecture of Haigh Jamgochian," by Barbara Ross Luck, Virginia Commonwealth University, M. A. Thesis, [Unbound], 1970. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - "The Artist In America," undated. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Book Review by Haigh Jamgochian for "Mr. Jefferson: Architect," by Desmond Guinness and Julius Trousdale Sadler, Jr., circa 1973. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - History and Appreciation of Art I, J. Sargent Reynolds Community College, Betty W. Cunningham, 1990. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - "How Does Aluminum Fit In With Architecture?" by Haigh Jamgochian, undated. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - "Imagination and Fact- An Experience Apart," by H. Karen Henderson, Medical College of Virginia- School of Nursing, 1967. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - "It's About Time We Did Something, Virginia," Emphasis, by Haigh Jamgochian, circa 1968. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - "Little and Big," by Haigh Jamgochian, circa 1993. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - "The Markel Building By Haigh Jamgochian, Architect, 1965," by Ginny Ross, 2001. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - [On The Markel Building project] by Haigh Jamgochian, circa 1965. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Project Proposal, Architectural and Environmental Arts, undated. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - ["Three billion years ago..."] by Haigh Jamgochian, circa 1962. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Speech Notes, circa 1962. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - "Tree House Apartment" by Haigh Jamgochian, circa 1962. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "What Is Architecture?" by Haigh Jamgochian, undated. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Subseries F. Miscellaneous, 1944-1986, undated., 3 folders.
    Contains miscellaneous materials related to Jamgochian's professional career, including a television news interview on the near-30th anniversary of the Markel Building.
    Arranged alphabetically by folder title with miscellaneous at the end.
    - Sign, undated. (Map-case 20, Drawer 8, Folder 3)
    - WTVR Newscast, circa 1989., 1 VHS tape; counter 0471-0541 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      Segment of Channel 6 (WTVR) newscast titled "Richmond After Six" hosted by Charles Fishburne. Reporter Jeff Moore discusses near 30 year anniversary of the Markel Building and Jamgochian's architectural career. Moon House and unfinished Amoeba House are also shown. Various models and drawings are also shown in the segment.
    - Miscellaneous, 1944-1986. (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Series IV. Project Records, 1949-1996., Extent: 20 boxes and 3 map case drawers. (Box 14-29)
  This series contains five subseries of project records created Haigh Jamgochian. Organized into subseries for Files, Photographs, Drawings, Models, and Clippings.
  - Subseries A. Files, circa 1949-1989., 5 boxes.
    Contains the surviving correspondence, notes, specifications, reports, and other project related materials for architectural projects designed by Jamgochian. Documented in this subseries are numerous projects that were not constructed by the clients. The following is restricted due to privacy issues: Communications Executive Center, Personal Financial Statement of Haigh Jamgochian, 1983. Especially well-documented in this subseries are the "Tree House," Markel Building, Moon House, and Communications Executive Center.
    - Town House Delicatessen, circa 1949. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Paris Prize Competition, 1953-1954. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 210 East Franklin St., circa 1954. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Archer Road Property, circa 1956. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Berkeley Building [932 West Franklin/329 North Harrison Sts.], 1956-1957. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 400 Lombardy St. [Stuart Circle], circa 1957-1958. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial Competition,, 1960. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "Tree House" Design, 1962-1964. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - "Tree House" Design, 1965-1966. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "Tree House" Design,, 1967-1968. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - "Tree House" Design, 1968-1981. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - "Tree House" Design, undated. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Westhaven Lake, Hanover Co., 1963-1968. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - "Amoeba House", 1964-1966. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - "Floating Building", 1964. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Markel Building, 1964. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Markel Building, 1965. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Markel Building, 1965. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Markel Building, 1966. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Markel Building, 1967-1968. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Markel Building, 1972-1989, undated. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Markel Building, Historic Marker Dedication,, 2006. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Moon House [Howard Hughes Residence], 1965-1967. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Moon House [Howard Hughes Residence], 1968. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Moon House [Howard Hughes Residence], 1971-1990. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Narrows Point Marina, 1965-1968. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Moorefield Apartments, 1967. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Bradley, O. M., 1968. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Israel, Tom [7-Eleven Store], circa 1971. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Chrysler, Taras [3620 Chellowe Rd.], 1973-1990. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Customized Masonry Design Contest, National Concrete Masonry Association, Arlington, VA, 1974. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Spider Museum [Morton, Ann], 1974-1984. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - 7363 Longview Dr. [Rockfalls Property], 1975, 1995-1997. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Communications Executive Center, 1983. (Box 16, Folder 9)
      Personal Financial Statement of Haigh Jamgochian RESTRICTED until 12 December 2024.
    - Communications Executive Center, January 1984-May 1984. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Communications Executive Center, June 1984-July 1984. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Communications Executive Center, August 1984. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Communications Executive Center, September 1984-November 1984. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Communications Executive Center, 1985. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Communications Executive Center, circa 1985. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Communications Executive Center, circa 1985. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Communications Executive Center, circa 1985. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Communications Executive Center, circa 1985. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Communications Executive Center, 1986-1991. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - 2310 Monument Ave., circa 1984. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - 2610 Monument Ave., 1984-1985. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Bandazian, Bedros, 1984-1985. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - St. James Armenian Church, 1984. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Silas Deane Highway Design Competition, Wethersfield, CT, 1984. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Harris, Welford L., 1984-1985. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - 603 North 34th St., 1985. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Broad Street Facade Renovation Project, 1985. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Stonewall Executive Square, Hanover Co., 1985. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - "Trump-et", 1988-1989. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Subseries B. Photographs, circa 1949-1988., 3 boxes.
    Contains photographic representations of structures, models, and renderings executed by architect Jamgochian. The two built projects, the Markel Building and Moon House, also have extensive construction photographs. Oversized photographs are noted.
    - Town House Delicatessen, circa 1949. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 400 Lombardy St. [Stuart Circle], circa 1957-1958. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial Competition, 1960. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - 8 East Franklin St., circa 1961-1962. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "Tree House" Design, circa 1962-1964. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "Tree House" Design, circa 1962-1964. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - "Tree House" Design [Duplicates], circa 1962-1964. (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - "Tree House" Design, circa 1962-1964. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - "Tree House" Design [Duplicates], circa 1962-1964. (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - "Floating Building", circa 1963. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Markel Building [First Design], circa 1963. (Map-case 20, Drawer 8, Folder 4)
    - Markel Building [Final Design], circa 1965. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Markel Building [Final Design], circa 1965. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Markel Building [Final Design], circa 1965. (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Markel Building [Final Design], circa 1965. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Moon House [Howard Hughes Residence], circa 1967-1968. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Moon House [Howard Hughes Residence], circa 1968. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Executive Communications Center, circa 1984-1985. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Communications Executive Center, circa 1985. (Map-case 20, Drawer 8, Folder 5)
    - Broad Street Facade Renovation Project, circa 1985. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - West Coast Gateway Design Competition, 1988. (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified Apartment Buildings, undated. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Subseries C. Drawings, 1949-1988, undated., 3 boxes and 5 map case drawers.
    Contains an extensive number of drawing, plans, shop drawings, and sketches for built and unbuilt projects designed by architect Jamgochian. Especially well-documented are the "Tree House," Markel Building, Moon House, and Communications Executive Center. Numerous other projects that did not make it past the proposal stage are also documented in this voluminous subseries. All projects, including those that pre-date Jamgochian's professional status, are organized in this subseries for ease of research. An example of a pre-professional project is the architect's work for his parents at the Town House Delicatessen, circa 1949. All drawing types and stages are housed together since most did not make it beyond the planning stage. In the case of completed projects with ample documentation, the drawings have been housed in multiple folders and separated by working and record drawings. The "Amoeba House" design was proposed for a parcel in Richmond's Forest Hill neighborhood and on the Rockfalls Drive property. Consequently, researcher can find information on this design, mostly photographs, in Series I, Subseries F. Photographs, Rockfalls Property, 1968-.
    - Town House Delicatessen, circa 1949. (Map-case 20, Drawer 9, Folder 1)
    - Richmond City Schools, 1953. (Map-case 20, Drawer 9, Folder 2)
    - Paris Prize Competition, 1954. (Map-case 20, Drawer 9, Folder 3)
    - Stern, Henry, circa 1955. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Westover Hills, 1955-1956. (Map-case 20, Drawer 9, Folder 4)
      See also "Amoeba House." This project represents the architect's first design for this site. About a decade later, the architect designed "The Amoeba" for the same site.
    - Archer Road Property, circa 1956. (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Berkeley Building [923 W. Franklin St./329 N. Harrison St.], 1956-1957. (Map-case 20, Drawer 9, Folder 5)
    - 400 Lombardy St. [Stuart Circle], circa 1957-1958. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Chautauaqua and Elm Aves., Princess Anne Co., circa 1959. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial Competition, circa 1960. (Map-case 20, Drawer 9, Folder 6)
    - Confederate States Ltd., 1961-1962. (Map-case 20, Drawer 9, Folder 7)
    - Cottrell Electronics, 1961. (Map-case 20, Drawer 9, Folder 8)
    - 8 East Franklin St., 1962. (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Oxford Hills Subdivision, 1962. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Sterling Development Corp., 1962. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - "Tree House" Design, circa 1962-1963. (Map-case 20, Drawer 10, Folder 1)
    - Benton, William, circa 1963-1965. (Map-case 20, Drawer 10, Folder 2)
    - Bernstein, H. J., circa 1963. (Map-case 20, Drawer 10, Folder 3)
    - "Floating Building", circa 1963-1964. (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Markel Building [First Design], Working Drawings, circa 1962-1971. (Map-case 20, Drawer 10, Folder 4)
    - Markel Building [Final Design], Working Drawings, circa 1963-1966. (Map-case 20, Drawer 10, Folder 5)
    - Markel Building [Final Design], Record Set, 1965. (Map-case 20, Drawer 11, Folder 1)
    - Richmond Aviation, Inc., 1963-1964. (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Westhaven Lake, Hanover Co., circa 1963. (Map-case 20, Drawer 11, Folder 2)
    - Bethlehem Steel Building, 1964. (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Bradley Building [2920 W. Broad St.], 1964. (Map-case 20, Drawer 11, Folder 3)
    - Moon House [Howard Hughes Residence], circa 1964-1967. (Map-case 20, Drawer 11, Folder 4)
    - Moyer, R. W., 1964. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - West Broad Tower, 1964. (Map-case 20, Drawer 11, Folder 5)
    - Hening, J. Garland, 1965. (Map-case 20, Drawer 11, Folder 6)
    - Narrows Point Marina, 1966. (Map-case 20, Drawer 11, Folder 7)
    - "Amoeba" House, 1967. (Map-case 20, Drawer 12, Folder 1)
    - Harris, Welford L., 1967. (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Moorefield Apartments, 1967. (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Harden, Robert and Diane, circa 1968-1971. (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Highland Springs,, 1971. (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Israel, Tom [7-Eleven Store], circa 1971. (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - 7363 Longview Dr. [Rockfalls Property], 1972-1997. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Customized Masonry Design Contest, National Concrete Masonry Assoc., Arlington, VA, circa 1974. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Texaco Station,, circa 1974. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Dolsey, Dr. Bernard, 1978. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - 2610 Monument Ave., 1984-1985. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Bandazian, Bedros, 1984-1985. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - St. James Armenian Church, 1984. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Silas Deane Highway Design Competition [Wethersfield, CT], 1984. (Map-case 20, Drawer 12, Folder 2)
    - Spider Museum [Ann Moreton], Powhatan, VA, circa 1984. (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - 105 N. Robinson St., Richmond, 1985. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - 603 N. 34th St., Richmond, 1985. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Broad Street Facade Renovation Project, circa 1985. (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Communications Executive Center, 1985. (Map-case 20, Drawer 12, Folder 3)
    - Star House, circa 1985. (Map-case 20, Drawer 12, Folder 4)
    - Stonewall Executive Square, Hanover Co., VA, circa 1985. (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Rhodes, Joyce, 1987. (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - "Trump-et", 1988-1989. (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - West Coast Gateway Design Competition, 1988. (Map-case 20, Drawer 13, Folder 1)
    - Chrysler, Taras [3620 Chellowe Rd.], 1990. (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - 4508 Forest Hill Ave., 1991. (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Greentree's Mens Store, undated. (Map-case 20, Drawer 13, Folder 2)
    - Steven Kent Motor Lodge, undated. (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified Apartment Building, undated. (Map-case 20, Drawer 13, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified Office Building, undated. (Map-case 30, Drawer 13, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1955-1966. (Map-case 20, Drawer 13, Folder 5)
  - Subseries D. Models, circa 1962-1990., 8 Oversize boxes.
    Contains architectural models for eight projects proposed by the architect. These models were all designed and constructed by the architect. Considerable care should be used with these fragile objects.
    - Tree House, circa 1962., Height: 21 in., Width: 16 in.; Materials: cardboard, plastic, wood. (Box 22)
    - Revolving Hotel, circa 1963., Height: 15 in., Width: 24 in.; Materials: cardboard, plastic, wood, metal. (Box 23)
    - Markel Building [first design], circa 1964., Height: 17.5 in., Diameter: 30 in.; Materials: cardboard, plastic, metal, wood. (Map-case 24 (top))
    - Markel Building [final design], circa 1965., Height: 3 in., Width: 6.5 in; Materials: wood, foam, aluminum. (Box 24)
    - Moon House, circa 1968., Height: 2 in., Width: 19.5 in.; Materials: cardboard, plastic, aluminum, wood. (Box 25)
    - Mobile Housing Pod, circa 1971., Diameter: 14 in. each; Materials: cardboard, plastic. (Box 26)
      This box contains two models related to Jamgochian's M. A. thesis, " A Neighborhood for Richmond, Virginia," 1951. Their creation date is unknown, but it is known that they were displayed at the 27 March 1971 Richmond Public Forum lecture titled "It's Our World: let's talk about it...with Dr. Isaac Asimov." See Series III, G. Miscellaneous.
    - Communications Executive Center, circa 1984., Height: 21.5 in.; Materials: metal, paper, plastic, Styrofoam. (Box 27)
    - Star House, circa 1985., Height: 3.5 in., Width: 11 in.; Materials: cardboard, metal, wood. (Box 28)
  - Subseries E. Clippings, 1962-1996., 1 box.
    Contains newspaper clippings related to specific architectural projects. The majority pertain to the "Tree House," Markel Building, Moon House, and Communications Executive Center.
    - "Tree House" Design, 1962-1968. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - "Floating Building", 1963. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Markel Building,, 1964-1986, undated. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Moon House, 1967-1990. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Communications Executive Center, 1971-1984. (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Communications Executive Center, 1984-1996. (Box 29, Folder 6)
- Series V. Rockfalls School, circa 1971-1974., Extent: 1 box. (Box 30)